# Mikaila K Ivery

### Front-End Developer

Brooklyn, New York · iverymikaila@gmail.com · @ mikailaivery.com

Front-end developer with proven experience in helping companies create and maintain a better code base for reusability. Capable of bridging any knowledge gaps through continuous learning from senior developers while still coaching novice developers. Experience in facilitating projects from concept to launch. Passionate about learning and growth with a desire to apply skills on a larger development team.

Key Skills HTML CSS JavaScript SEO Git Version Control

Responsive Design RESTful APIs JSON

React.js Adobe Creative Suite UX/UI Design

#### **Experience**

#### Freelance Web Developer, Boy Blondey co

Feb 2022 - Present

Boy Blondey is an indie menswear brand that sells clothing that expresses a tenderness for the past through the study of Historical Black Cultures and soulful tailoring.

- Developed user interfaces with custom HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in the company's Shopify theme template which improved user satisfaction.
- Created accessible, responsive, and functional code that allowed web visitors on any device to have the same user experience.
- Designed and coded custom HTML email templates that work with any email provider.
- Maintained quality website functionality through ongoing updates and troubleshooting.

#### Freelance Web Developer, Orée Nyc

**Sept 2023** 

Orée Nyc is a popular menswear brand that celebrates elegance through simple and functional clothes.

- Designed and coded web designs/ wireframes using custom HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Adobe Photoshop for the company website.
- Worked as part of a 4 person team and communicated in a professional and collegial way.
- Intergrated custom code through Wix web development software.

#### Freelance Web Developer, Waist Away by Moojy

May 2023 - Jul 2023

Waist Away by Moojy is a chic shape-wear brand that sells top-quality products that enhance your natural beauty, while also promoting self-love and body positivity.

- Developed and designed custom HTML, CSS, and Javascript for the brand's Shopify theme template.
- Maintained quality website functionality through ongoing updates and troubleshooting.
- Use keywords, tags, and meta-descriptions in order to optimize website for search engine and ranking.

#### **Education**

#### University

### Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, Western Governors University

August 2023 - Expected Dec 2024

Western Governors University is a private, non-profit, online university based in Millcreek, Utah. The university uses an online competency-based learning model.

- Study of engineering principles to design, develop, test, and analyze computer software.
- Gaining industry certifications including AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, CompTIA Project+, and ITIL® Foundation Certification.
- Learning technologies such as C#, Node js, Python, SQL, and more.
- Relevant Coursework: Data structures and algorithms, Software Design and Quality Assurance, Cloud Foundations.etc.

## Associate of Applied Science in Advertising Marketing Communications, August 2019 - Dec 2021 Fashion Institute of Technology

The Fashion Institute of Technology is a public college in New York City. It is part of the SUNY schools of New York and focuses on art, business, design, mass communication, and technology.

- Study of advertising, public relations, broadcasting, journalism, digital media, management, and international organizations.
- Nominated NSLS member by the school dean.
- Overall GPA of 3.4

Certifications	Web Development Certificate	2021 - 2022
Ceruncanons	Web Development Certificate	2021-2022

Issued by SheCodes Workshops

HTML Email Bootcamp 2022

Issued by Noble Desktop

Foundation of Leadership Certificate 2021

Issued by National Society of Leadership and Success (NSLS)

School Projects Weather App

Technologies: Open Weather Map API, React.js

Source Code: GitHub

**Dictionary App** 

Technologies: Dictionary API, React.js

Source Code: GitHub

**References** Available on request.